Guide to the Royal College of Art Sketch Club Collection
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- Albert Rutherston letter to unidentified recipient, Rutherston, Albert, 1881-1953; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 21 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 74)
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Rutherston, Albert, 1881-1953 -- Correspondence
- Randolph Schwabe letter to Frank B. Mason, 1934 July 9; Schwabe, Randolph, 1885-1948; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 75)
  Schwabe tells Mason he will give two guineas for a "special prize, for the same subject as before."
  Letterhead: "20, Church Row, Hampstead, N.W.3., Hampstead 5320."
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Schwabe, Randolph, 1885-1948 -- Correspondence; Mason, Frank B. -- Correspondence
- Randolph Schwabe postcard to J. Anthony Denney, 1935 November 12; Schwabe, Randolph, 1885-1948; 1 postcard: autograph postcard, signed; 9 x 14 cm (Box 1, Folder 76)
  Schwabe informs Denney of his plans to come to the exhibition.
  Letterhead: "University of London, University College, Telephone No. museum 8101, Gower Street, London, W.C.1"
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Schwabe, Randolph, 1885-1948 -- Correspondence; Denney, Anthony, 1913-1990 -- Correspondence
- Randolph Schwabe letter to Evelyn Hunt, 1937 October 4; Schwabe, Randolph, 1885-1948; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 77)
  Schwabe encloses "the usual amount of prize money" on "the subject to be as before, unless you would like a change."
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Schwabe, Randolph, 1885-1948 -- Correspondence; Hunt, Evelyn Janet, 1914-2001 -- Correspondence
- Randolph Schwabe postcard to Evelyn Hunt, 1937 November 11; Schwabe, Randolph, 1885-1948; 1 postcard: autograph postcard, signed; 9 x 14 cm (Box 1, Folder 78)
  Schwabe informs Hunt of his plans to come to the exhibition.
- William G. Simmonds letter to Joseph Jago, 1934 July 23; Simmonds, W. G. (William George), 1876-1968; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 18 x 23 cm (Box 1, Folder 79)
  Simmonds agrees to send a check (at a later date) for a prize for the best note book drawings.
  Letterhead: "The Frith, Far Oakridge, Stroud, Glos."
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Simmonds, W. G. (William George), 1876-1968 -- Correspondence; Jago, Joseph -- Correspondence
- William G. Simmonds letter to Frank B. Mason, 1934 October 13; Simmonds, W. G. (William George), 1876-1968; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 12 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 80)
  Simmonds sends a check for the exhibition, and discusses when he will be in London.
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Simmonds, W. G. (William George), 1876-1968 -- Correspondence; Mason, Frank B. -- Correspondence
- William G. Simmonds letter to J. Anthony Denney, 1935 July 8; Simmonds, W. G. (William George), 1876-1968; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 18 x 23 cm (Box 1, Folder 81)
  Simmonds sends a check for a prize awarded to the "best note book drawings (in the book)."
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Simmonds, W. G. (William George), 1876-1968 -- Correspondence; Denney, Anthony, 1913-1990 -- Correspondence
- Sydney Press letter to Joseph Jago, 1934 Oct 19; 1 sheet (1 page): printed letter; 21 x 13 cm (Box 1, Folder 82)
  The form letter requests: "Please examine the enclosed proofs carefully and make any alterations you find necessary […]"
  Letterhead: "Electric Printing Works. Sydney Press. 24, Cale Street, Chelsea, S.W.3."
- Hubert Wellington letter to Frank B. Mason, 1934 July 6; Wellington, Hubert, 1879-; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 26 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 83)
  Wellington agrees to continue his prize in painting for two guineas.
  Letterhead includes image of castle (presumably seal of Edinburgh College of Art) and: "The Edinburgh College of Art, Lauriston Place, Edinburgh.3. Telephone No. 32471"
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Wellington, Hubert, 1879- -- Correspondence; Mason, Frank B. -- Correspondence
- Hubert Wellington letter to J. Anthony Denney, 1935 July 21; Wellington, Hubert, 1879-; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 18 x 14 cm (Box 1, Folder 84)
  Wellington agrees to continue his prize and encloses two guineas for the painting section of the show.
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Wellington, Hubert, 1879- -- Correspondence; Denney, Anthony, 1913-1990 -- Correspondence
- Hubert Wellington letter to Evelyn Hunt, 1937 October 11; Wellington, Hubert, 1879-; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 26 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 85)
  Wellington agrees to continue his prize and, as he will not be in London for the show, suggests John Nash as a suitable judge. He also says he must stop sponsoring a prize after this year given his growing duties at his college.
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Wellington, Hubert, 1879- -- Correspondence; Hunt, Evelyn Janet, 1914-2001 -- Correspondence; Nash, John, 1893-1977
- R.H. Wilenski letter to Frank B. Mason, 1934 July 18; Wilenski, R. H. (Reginald Howard), 1887-1975; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 16 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 86)
  Wilenski suggests he should be free to judge for the show, but "as regards the prize I do not quite understand what you want me to do." He requests a further discussion.
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Wilenski, R. H. (Reginald Howard), 1887-1975 -- Correspondence; Mason, Frank B. -- Correspondence
- J.P. Willcock letter to J. Anthony Denney, 1935 July 5; Willcock, J. P.; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 25 x 20 cm (Box 1, Folder 87)
  Willcock informs Denney that the North Court of the V&A Museum has been reserved for the RCA Sketch Club.
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Willcock, J. P. -- Correspondence; Denney, Anthony, 1913-1990 -- Correspondence; Victoria and Albert Museum
- Note by an unidentified author on costumes and settings for a contemporary play, between 1934 and 1937?; 1 sheet (1 page); 19 x 12 cm (Box 1, Folder 88)
  A short note written in graphite: "Sketch Club. Costumes and settings for a contemporary play." A different hand has appended the words "mine" (pointing to "costumes") and "Bawden's" (pointing to "settings"). In a third hand, the foot is annotated with the words "Bawden + Ravilious" -- i.e., Edward Bawden and Eric Ravilious.
  Letterhead: "Royal College of Art, South Kensington, London, S.W.7."
  Notes; Theaters -- Stage-setting and scenery; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Bawden, Edward, 1903-1989; Ravilious, Eric William, 1903-1942